Chris Phillips

Software Engineer

678-409-8713 | phillipsachris@gmail.com | https://cphillips.dev
https://cphillips.dev
https://cphillips.dev
https://cphillips.dev

I design modular, performant web applications with experience in working on both ends of the stack. I have shipped production code with methodologies from both object oriented and functional programming. I am inspired to constantly learn and improve my skills to ensure that complex, web-scale systems are healthy, monitored, and automated.

Technical Skills

Languages: Javascript, Python, Typescript, Java, SQL, Bash, HTML/CSS

Frameworks/Runtimes: Node, React, Next.js, Express, Mongoose, Luigi, Django

Dev Tools: Git, AWS, Docker, Postman, Jenkins

Experience

Software Engineer | Built Technologies

February 2022 – Present

- Create ETO pipelines for data conversion with Python, MySQL and Docker images with client data
- Utilize Python for onboarding and prop loading messy data and reports into a standardized format
- Utilize AWS to merge files into SQL database and ensure platform and full suite of products can use data

Software Application Engineer | Workday

June 2021 – Dec 2021

- Utilize Java and its libraries in programming frameworks and adhere to object oriented principles
- Employ specialized tools to create and improve web services using REST and SOAP protocol
- Employ agile methodologies in cross functional team with platforms like Jira, Crucible, Github, etc

Software Engineer | Volo Sports

May 2021 - June 2021

- Implemented frontend changes and various APIs to improve site usability and end user experience
- Created MongoDB queries on the backend connected with GraphQL
- Utilized React as a framework in combination with Node.js, Mongoose, and Express MVC

Software Engineer Immersive Fellow | General Assembly

Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

- Three-month, 420-hour full-time and full-stack program conducted in a remote setting
- Gained experience with the latest front-end and back-end programming languages, tools, and methodologies
- Created Code Finesse Github organization to help new engineers learn fundamentals

Associate Director | Via Services

April 2019 - May 2020

- Directed special needs camp of up to 70 campers and 75 staff across all departments at a time
- Implemented program curriculum to meet grant outcomes, mission delivery, and budget goals
- Managed overall programming budget and ordered and inventoried necessary equipment for camp activities, grant requirements, and day to day operations

Insight Facilitator | Outward Bound

January 2018 - April 2019

- Oversaw the design and facilitation of over 30 team building blocks as the Lead Insight Facilitator
- Set up over 10 partnerships and service project days as the Youth Leadership Cohort Coordinator
- Completed six seasons of guiding students through leadership and communication based experiences

Education

General Assembly | Remote
Software Engineering Immersive
University of North Carolina at Greensboro | Greensboro, North Carolina
Psychology

October 2020 - December 2020

August 2013 - May 2016